

Taeyoung Kim

ROBOTICS · SLAM ENGINEER

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9686-8177 | **I**tyoung96@yonsei.ac.kr | **A** taeyoung96.github.io | **D** Taeyoung96

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

Summary.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become robotics SLAM engineer. My research interests are Sensor fusion and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I'm also interested in contributing open-source projects.

Research Interests

SLAM LiDAR SLAM, LiDAR-inertial SLAM, Visual SLAM, Visual-inertial SLAM

Sensor fusion Combination of Camera, LiDAR, or IMU sensor

Computer Vision Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation, 3D reconstruction

Education

Yonsei University @CILAB

Seoul, S.Korea

M.S. IN VEHICLE CONVERGENCE ENGINEERING (ADVISOR: PROF. EUNTAI KIM)

Mar. 2022 - Feb. 2024 (Expected)

- Join the mobile robot team
- · Research on LiDAR-inertial odometry

Kwang Woon University

Seoul, S.Korea

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022

- Total GPA: 4.10 / 4.50, Major GPA: 4.41 / 4.50
- **Club**: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) [2020 Staff] , DAISY (English Conversation Club) [2019 Spring President]

Work Experience

Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

UNDERGRADUATE LAB INTERN (ADVISOR: PROF. SANGPIL KIM)

Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Research on Computer Vision using an Event camera
- Event data processing using ESIM

KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR : DR. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

Projects

Development of Core Technology for Mobile Manipulator for 5G Edge-based Transportation and Manipulation

Ministry of Science and ICT

PARTICIPANT

Apr. 2022 - Feb. 2024

• Development LiDAR-inertial odometry algorithm for Mobile Manipulator

LiDAR-inertial SLAM algorithm robust to 6-DOF rotation changes

Hyundai Robotics LAB May. 2022 - Feb.2023

PARTICIPANT

• Development LiDAR-inertial odometry algorithm for 6-DOF roataion changes

MAY 29, 2022 TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE

Publication

INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL

"Standard for the Quantification of a Sterilization Effect Using an Artificial Intelligence Disinfection

2021.11 Robot", Heeju Hong, Wonkook Shin, Jieun Oh, Sunwoo Lee, Taeyoung Kim, Woosub Lee, Jongsuk Choi, Sensors Seungbeum Suh and Kanggeon Kim, Sensors 21, no. 23: 7776. https://doi.org/10.3390/s21237776

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

"Dense Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation", UR 2021 2021.7 Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim, - [Paper], [Video] (Work in progress)

DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

"Recognition of disinfection targets and generation of semantic map for disinfection robot", 2021.5 KROS 2021 TaeHwan Kim, Taeyoung Kim, GiJae Lee, KangGeon Kim, - [Paper]

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

2020.11 Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
2020.9 5th Place on B-track , Korea Health Datathon 2020	NAVER CLOUD
Stil Place on B-track, Rolled Health Datathon 2020	PLATFORM
2019.10 Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.

Honors

2022-1	Full tuition Scholarship,	Hyundai NGV
	for the students who have been based on Recruitment Conditions on Hyundai Motors Group	riyunaar NGV
2021-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship,	Korea Student Aid
2021-1	for the students who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2020-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship,	Korea Student Aid
2020-1	for the students who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2019-2	Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester	KwangWoon Univ.

Skills

Programming C++ / C, Python, JAVA, Matlab **Framework** Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras **DevOps** Git, Docker, ROS2 / ROS Languages Korean, English

Extracurricular Activity _____

Technical Blogs Github blog

• You can easily access the blog using [this link].

· Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.

• To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

2021 Open Source Contribution Academy

Aug. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- · I am in the process of translating a Pytorch tutorial into Korean that I want to contribute to the spread of PyTorch.
- Using Github, I developed the ability to collaborate and contribute to open source.
- The open source repository I've contributed can be found [here].

CLOVA AI RUSH 2021 NAVER AI Lab, NAVER CLOVA

• Only 150 students are allowed to participate in this project.

- I developed my own deep learning model related to multi-label classification.
- I ranked 30th on Project 1-3.

PARTICIPANT

MAY 29, 2022 TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE

Ministry of Science and ICT

May. 2021 - Jun.2021

May. 2020 - Present

KwangWoon Univ.

PROJECT *Mar.* 2021 - Jun.2021

- I made a wireless charging electric vehicle charging robot.
- I designed the control input algorithm, trained deep learning model, and developed the ROS package.
- The source code related to this project is on my [Github repository].

Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.
- I used 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

Personal Toy Project Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].